Guide to the Memory Project Oral History collection, 2009-2016 | 民间记忆计划口述史 RL.10171
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Hunan province | 湖南省, 2009-2016
  - Changxing Village | 株洲市茶陵县高陇镇长兴村, 2010-2012
    - Zhou Jianying | 周俭英, 2010
      Zhou Jianying (b. 1934), the older sister of another interviewee, Zhou Xueying, is a resident of Changxing Village, Gaolong Town, Chaling County, Hunan Province. Zhou was born in the nearby Zhoubi Town, and married a man in Changxing Village in 1952. In 1958, Zhou worked for the production team during pregnancy until labor. Her working points were deducted because of going back home to feed her child. In 1960, Zhou's husband with several other villagers escaped to Jinggang Mountain of Jiangxi Province, where they could get more food by participating in the construction work. Zhou was punished to work more as the wife of the escaped criminal. During this period, some peasants from the nearby You County came to Changixing Village to sell their clothes and children because of the famine. She remembers that during the Cultural Revolution, the Red Flag Army, leaders of the Land Reform, were criticized.
      周俭英（1934年生）是湖南省茶陵县高陇镇长兴村村民。她是另一位受访人——周雪英——的姐姐，1952年从隔壁的州比镇嫁到长兴村。周老人的口述包括大跃进、大饥荒和文革三个主题。1958年，周老人怀着孩子参加生产队劳动，一直到临产；生产后因为在工作间隙回家给孩子喂奶被扣工分。1960年，周老人的丈夫和很多同乡逃去江西井冈山，因为在那里参加建设给饭吃；而周老人作为逃犯家属，被生产队惩罚参加劳动。该时期长兴村附近的攸县的农民，有的担着衣服和孩子到这里来卖。另外，周老人还讲述了文革期间，批斗'红旗军'——土改时期的干部——的情况。
    - Zhou Xueying | 周雪英, 2010
      Zhou Xueying (b. 1940) is a resident of Changxing Village, Gaolong Town, Chaling County, Hunan Province. She was born in a nearby town called Zhoubi, and married to a man in Changxing Village in 1961. In this interview, Zhou recalls how she raised rabbits for a state farm, which was established in Zhoubi Town in 1958, and how this state farm distributed more grains than other People's Communes.
      周雪英（1940年生）是湖南省茶陵县高陇镇长兴村村民，1961年从隔壁的州比镇嫁到长兴村。在这段口述中，周老人讲述了自己1958年在州比镇的国营农场养兔子的经历，以及1960年粮食最为匮乏的时期，周老人所在的国营农场发放的粮食比其他公社稍多的情况。
    - Zhou Nianying | 周年英, 2010
      Zhou Nianying (b. 1940) is a resident of Changxing Village, Gaolong Town, Chaling County, Hunan Province. She was born in a nearby town called Zhoubi, and married to a man in Changxing Village in 1957. In this interview, Zhou recalls how she participated in constructing blast furnace as a pregnant woman during the Great Leap Forward, and how she starved for limited food supplies during the Great Famine.
      周年英（1940年生）是湖南省茶陵县高陇镇长兴村村民，1957年从隔壁的州比镇嫁到长兴村。在这段口述中，周老人讲述了大跃进期间自己怀着身孕参加大炼钢铁，以及大饥荒期间因粮食匮乏挨饿的经历。
  - Jimingqiao Village | 常德市石门县白云乡鸡鸣桥村, 2009-2010
    Jimingqiao Village is located in Shimen County, Changde City, Hunan Province. Interviews in this sub-series were conducted and filmed by Jia Zhitan.
    鸡鸣桥村位于湖南省常德市石门县白云乡。村民的录像采访人是贾之坦。
    - Jia Zhenci | 贾珍次, 2010
      Jia Zhenci (b. 1950) is a resident of Jimingqiao Village, Baiyun Town, Shimen County, Hunan Province. In this interview, Jia recalls how he vomited blood because of the hard work of transporting bamboo charcoal when constructing blast furnace in 1958, and how he used cedars cut in the mountain to exchange food coupons of the people's commune canteen in 1959. Jia also mentions that the bones of some villagers' ancestors were digged out of tombs and then boiled to make farming fertilizer. The filmmaker's description of this interview has been translated into English.
      贾珍次（1950年生）是湖南省石门县白云乡鸡鸣桥村村民。在这段口述中，贾老人回忆了1958年大炼钢铁时自己挑竹炭累得吐血，以及1959年兴办公社食堂时自己上山砍杉树换饭票的经历。另外，贾老人还讲述了有些村民的祖坟被挖、先人骨头被煮后做田地肥料的情况。
    - Jia Zhenwen | 贾珍文, 2009
      Jia Zhenwen (b. 1930) is a resident of Jimingqiao Village, Baiyun Town, Shimen County, Hunan Province. In this interview, Jia recalls the whole process of capturing Yang Guanyuan, the "counter-revolutionary."
      贾珍文（1930年生）是湖南省石门县白云乡鸡鸣桥村村民。在这段口述中，贾老人回忆了文革期间他见证到的抓捕"反革命分子"杨官元的全过程。
    - Jia Zhijie | 贾之杰, 2010
      Jia Zhijie (b. 1940) is a resident of Jimingqiao Village, Baiyun Town, Shimen County, Hunan Province. In this interview, Jia recalls how the local leaders mobilized villagers to construct the Heping Reservoir while stripping to the waist in the winter of 1959, and how the bones of some villagers' ancestors, were digged out of the tombs and boiled with dead dogs to make farming fertilizer in 1959, when the field output was decreasing. Jia also talks about how he, as the manager of the people's commune canteen, caught some villagers stealing the canteen's vegetables and staple food.
      贾之杰（1940年生）是湖南省石门县白云乡鸡鸣桥村村民。在这段口述中，贾老人回忆了1959年冬天当地干部号召村民赤膊上阵修和平水库，1959年农业减产后挖村民祖坟、打狗后熬骨头做成肥料种田的情况。贾老人还讲述了自己担任公社食堂事务长期间抓到偷食堂蔬菜和饭的村民。
    - Gong Zhaoxian | 龚兆先, 2011
      Gong Zhaoxian (b. 1945) is a resident of Jimingqiao Village, Baiyun Town, Shimen County, Hunan Province. In this interview, Gong recalls how she was starving at the people's commune cantee, and how her brother was reproached by the local leader for complaining about the canteen. The filmmaker's description of this interview has been translated into English.
      龚兆先（1945年生）是湖南省石门县白云乡鸡鸣桥村村民。在这段口述中，龚老人讲述了大跃进时期兴办公社食堂时吃不饱挨饿的经历。龚老人还回忆了自己的哥哥因为抱怨食堂制度被支书斥骂的情况。
    - Zhang Nianhe | 张年和, 2009
      Zhang Nianhe (b. 1948) a resident of Jimingqiao Village, Baiyun Town, Shimen County, Hunan Province. In this interview, Zhang recalls his experience during the Cultural Revolution. He was labeled as a counter-revolutionary and was sent to the countryside when working in the People's Hospital of Shimen County, for supporting the hospital head, Peng, who had been labeled as a capitalist roader. Later Peng became the head of the Police Department of the county, and revoked Zhang's counter-revolutionary record. The filmmaker's description of this interview has been translated into English.
      张年和（1948年生）是湖南省石门县白云乡鸡鸣桥村村民。在这段口述中，张老人回忆了文革期间他在石门县人民医院工作时，因为拥护被打成走资派的彭姓院长，被打成反革命下放农村。后来彭姓院长成为公安局长 ,撤销了他的反革命案底。
    - Zhou Chengshun | 周成顺, 2012
      Zhou Chengshun (b. 1940) is a resident of Jimingqiao Village, Baiyun Town, Shimen County, Hunan Province. During the Great Famine Zhou did not suffer from hunger thanks to his position as the director of the people's commune canteen. In his memory, no villager died of starvation in their canteen. Zhou also recalls that slogans were written on some young women's breasts to mobilize the workers at the construction site of Heping Reservoir in 1959.
      周成顺（1940年生）是湖南省石门县白云乡鸡鸣桥村村民。大饥荒时期周老人是当地食堂事务员，是不会挨饿的一类人，所以他的回忆中并没有饿死人的个例。不过他分享了一个大跃进时期的故事：1959年搞和平水库时，有年轻女性被的乳房上被写上口号给众人做宣传。
    - Zhou Qiaozhen | 周巧珍, 2010
      Zhou Qiaozhen (b. 1945) is a resident of Jimingqiao Village, Baiyun Town, Shimen County, Hunan Province. In this interview, Zhou recalls how her mother was caught by the local leaders because her going out begging for food brought shame to the government, how her brother committed suicide by hanging because he was afraid of being criticized for stealing two sweet potatoes, and how her father died from cave-in when producing charcoal.
      周巧珍（1945年生）是湖南省石门县白云乡鸡鸣桥村村民。在这段口述中，周老人讲述了兴建食堂时母亲出去要饭被干部抓到后送回来因为出了政府的丑，哥哥透了两个番薯后害怕被批斗上吊自杀，以及父亲烧炭被炭洞的塌方砸死的情况。
    - Wang Xiangzhen | 王香珍, 2011
      Wang Xiangzhen (b. 1938) is a resident of Jimingqiao Village, Baiyun Town, Shimen County, Hunan Province. In this interview, Wang recounts how the dinners to recall past bitterness eaten at the Chinese New Year, and the consequential conflict between her and her mother-in-law caused by a small bow of meat.
      王香珍（1938年生）是湖南省石门县白云乡鸡鸣桥村村民。在这段口述中，王老人回忆了兴办食堂时期过年吃"忆苦餐"，以及过年因为一小碗肉跟婆婆闹矛盾的故事。
    - Man Congying | 满从英, 2011
      Man Congying (b. 1952) is a resident of Jimingqiao Village, Baiyun Town, Shimen County, Hunan Province. In this interview, Man recalls how they eat wild herbs and tree bark to survive starvation, how her little brother was beaten by their father for eating more food, and how the production team leader threw their food away after catching she and her sisters cooking secretly at home.
      满从英（1952年生）是湖南省石门县白云乡鸡鸣桥村村民。在这段口述中，满老人回忆了大饥荒年间吃野菜和树皮度日，小弟弟抢家人饭吃被爸爸打，家里开小灶被队长掀翻的故事。
    - He Benli | 何本立, 2011
      He Benli (b. 1949) is a resident of Jimingqiao Village, Baiyun Town, Shimen County, Hunan Province. In this interview, He recalls how he collected vegetable leaves as food after the people's commune canteen was established in 1958. He also talks about a fellow villager, Li Juncai, who starved to death, and the village's warehouse guard, Yang Guanlin, who fed his family with the collective velvet antler.
      何本立（1949年生）是湖南省石门县白云乡鸡鸣桥村村民。在这段口述中，何老人讲述了1958年兴办食堂时自己捡菜叶子充饥的经历。何老人还介绍了村民李君才被饿死，及大队保管员杨官林利用职务便利弄鹿茸给家人吃的情况。
    - Liu Jinlan | 刘金兰, 2010
      Liu Jinlan (b. 1926) is a resident of Jimingqiao Village, Baiyun Town, Shimen County, Hunan Province. In this interview, Liu recalls she was starving at the people's commune cantee and had to eat wild herbs as food. Liu also talks about how she worked day and night in the production team.
      刘金兰（1926年生）是湖南省石门县白云乡鸡鸣桥村村民。在这段口述中，刘老人讲述了兴办食堂时吃不饱、吃野菜充饥，以及夜以继日地为生产队劳动的经历。
    - Mo Dejun | 莫德君, 2010
      Mo Dejun (b. 1924) is a resident of Jimingqiao Village, Baiyun Town, Shimen County, Hunan Province. In this interview, Mo recalls that he was dismissed from the position of the warehouse guard of the people's commune canteen because of other people's setup. After that he return to his village to work, but he was still criticized as a member of the Four Elements (landlords, rich peasants, counter-revolutionaries, and band elements) from 1959 to 1979. Mo also talks about a fellow villager, who committed suicide because he was accused of stealing food coupons.
      莫德君（1924年生）湖南省石门县白云乡鸡鸣桥村村民。在这段口述中，莫老人讲述了自己曾担任公社食堂保管员，被人陷害丢了职位后回村劳动，之后从1959到1979年间被作为"四种分子"接受批斗。莫老人还谈到了一位村民因为被指控偷饭票而上吊自杀的情况。
    - Mo Defang | 莫德芳, 2010
      Mo Defang (b. 1936) is a resident of Jimingqiao Village, Baiyun Town, Shimen County, Hunan Province. In this interview, Mo recalls how her house was pulled down during the Great Leap Forward, and how some villagers were criticized for not working hard for constructing the Heping Reservoir.
      莫德芳（1936年生）是湖南省石门县白云乡鸡鸣桥村村民。在这段口述中，莫老人回忆了大跃进时期房屋被拆，修和平水库时不努力就被批斗的情况。
    - Deng Dongzhen | 邓冬珍, 2010
      Deng Dongzhen (b. 1929) is a resident of Jimingqiao Village, Baiyun Town, Shimen County, Hunan Province. In this interview, Deng recounts how the kind staff of the people's commune canteen give her extra food coupons and sweet potatoes to feed her three children, how she collected sweet potatoes in the mountains, and how she stole beans and rice when cooking for the production team. The filmmaker's description of this interview has been translated into English.
      邓冬珍（1929年生）是湖南省石门县白云乡鸡鸣桥村村民。在这段口述中，邓老人讲述了公社食堂里的好心人偷偷给她饭票或番薯养活家里的三个孩子，自己偷偷去山顶上找番薯，给生产队种菜做饭时偷拿豆子、大米等的经历。
    - Wu Yangbo | 吴杨波, 2010
      Wu Yangbo (b. 1946) is a resident of Jimingqiao Village, Baiyun Town, Shimen County, Hunan Province. In this interview, Wu recounted how his family's house was pulled down and used as fertilizers when running the people's commune canteen, how he was forced drop out of middle school to work, how his family relied on neighbors' help after his mother lost food coupons for ten days, and how a relative committed suicide by hanging because he was accused for stealing other's food coupons. The filmmaker's description of this interview has been translated into English.
      吴杨波（1946年生）是湖南省石门县白云乡鸡鸣桥村村民。在这段口述中，吴老人讲述了因为生产队长——赵＊＊——在兴建公社食堂期间家里房屋被拆了做肥料，自己在中学里不读书被迫参加各种劳动，自己母亲把十天的饭票丢了全家靠人接济，以及一位亲戚被控偷了别人饭票上吊自杀的情况。
    - Wu Yumei | 吴玉梅, 2010
      Wu Yumei (b. 1942) is a resident of Jimingqiao Village, Baiyun Town, Shimen County, Hunan Province. In this interview, Wu recalls how she lived on the other family members' grains after she lost the food coupons for 10 days in 1959. During this period, some villagers were criticized for stealing sweet potatoes to eat, and several villagers died of starvation. Wu also recounts how leaders of the local production team were criticized orally and punished physically by the superior leaders because they failed to complete the production task during the Great Leap Forward. The filmmaker's description of this interview has been translated into English.
      吴玉梅（1942年生）是湖南省石门县白云乡鸡鸣桥村村民。在这段口述中，吴老人讲述了1958年兴办公社食堂时自己丢了十天的饭票后分吃家人的粮食过活的经历。该时期有村民因为偷吃番薯被批斗，也有几位村民挨饿致死。吴老人还回忆了大跃进时期生产任务没有完成、生产队干部被上级干部批斗体罚的情况。
    - Tang Taozhen | 唐桃珍, 2010
      Tang Taozhen (b. 1937) is a resident of Jimingqiao Village, Baiyun Town, Shimen County, Hunan Province. In this interview, Tang recalls how she cooked in the people's commune canteen, and how some villagers ate grass seeds because of starvation. Tang also recalls no babies were born during 1958 and 1961 because couples were working separately at different places and they were too starving.
      唐桃珍（1937年生）是湖南省石门县白云乡鸡鸣桥村村民。在这段口述中，唐老人讲述了自己在公社食堂做饭、有些村民吃草籽等充饥的情况。唐老人还提到1958年到1961年间村里夫妻因为异地劳动及吃不饱没有生育的情况。
    - Tian Hongzhen | 田宏珍, 2012
      Tian Hongzhen (b. 1943) is a resident of Jimingqiao Village, Baiyun Town, Shimen County, Hunan Province. In this interview, Tian recalls that both men and women were mobilized to strip to the waist when constructing the Heping Reservoir. Tian was spared thanks to her unmarried status.
      田宏珍（1943年生）是湖南省石门县白云乡鸡鸣桥村村民。在这段口述中，田老人回忆了大跃进时期修建和平水库，男女都得赤膊上阵的情况，田老人因为还未婚嫁才得以幸免。
    - Jia Zhitan | 贾之坦, 2010
      Jia Zhitan (b. 1951) is a resident of Zhuxiangkou Village, Baiyun Town, Shimen County, Hunan Province. In this interview, Jia recalls that his experiences when eating at the people's commune canteen.
      贾之坦（1951年生）是湖南省石门县白云乡竹巷口村村民。在这段口述中，贾回忆了公社食堂时期。
    - Cai Xiangjing | 才相进, 2010
      Cai Xiangjin (b. 1944) is a resident of Jimingqiao Village, Baiyun Town, Shimen County, Hunan Province. In this interview, Cai recalls how many sweet potatoes were left uncollected in the field because most labors in the village were busy with constructing blast furnace during the Great Leap Forward. In consequence, there were not enough grains in 1959 and the villagers had to eat tree bark.
      才相进（1944年生）是湖南省石门县白云乡鸡鸣桥村村民。在这段口述中，才老人回忆因为大炼钢铁村里没有足够的劳动力收割番薯，以至于1959年没粮食吃树皮的情况。
    - Cai Cuizhen | 才翠珍, 2010
      Cai Cuizhen (b. 1930) is a resident of Jimingqiao Village, Baiyun Town, Shimen County, Hunan Province. In this interview, Cai recalls her experience of cooking in the people's commune canteen and at the reservoir construction site. Cai also mentioned her mother-in-law, who died of starvation during the period of commune canteen.
      才翠珍（1930年生）是湖南省石门县白云乡鸡鸣桥村村民。在这段口述中，才老人讲述了自己在人民公社食堂和水库工地做饭的经历。才老人也谈到自己的婆婆吃食堂时饿死的情况。
    - Li Zineng | 李子能, 2010
      Li Zineng (b. 1935) is a resident of Jimingqiao Village, Baiyun Town, Shimen County, Hunan Province. In this interview, Li recalls how he participated in the project of maintaining Dongting Lake in 1954 and how he fed pigs at the pig farm after the people's commune canteen was established in 1958. Li also talks about how the dead bodies of dogs, which were beaten to death, were boiled with soybean and lime to make farming fertilizer, and how some villagers were criticized because of planting vegetables for themselves.
      李子能（1935年生）是湖南省石门县白云乡鸡鸣桥村村民。在这段口述中，李老人讲述了1954年参加洞庭湖治理工程及1958年兴办公社食堂自己在猪场喂猪的经历。李老人还谈到了当地把狗打死后用黄豆和石灰一起煮了做农田肥料，以及有村民私自种菜遭批斗的情况。
    - Li Zichun | 李子春, 2010
      Li Zichun (b. 1943) is a resident of Jimingqiao Village, Baiyun Town, Shimen County, Hunan Province. In this interview, Li recalls how the production team digged out dead bodies from tombs to make farming fertilizers during the Great Leap Forward, how his family survived the Great Famine through stealing sweet potatoes and collecting tares, and how he exchanged bed frames, made from his house's beams, for grains. The filmmaker's description of this interview has been translated into English.
      李子春（1943年生）湖南省石门县白云乡鸡鸣桥村村民。在这段口述中，李老人回忆了大跃进时期大队熬死人骨头做肥料、大饥荒时期家里人通过偷番薯割稗子而免于被饿死、以及老人拆屋梁做床换粮食的情况。
    - Qin Shiju | 覃士菊, 2010
      Qin Shiju (b. 1933) is a resident of Jimingqiao Village, Baiyun Town, Shimen County, Hunan Province. In this interview, Qin recounts how her husband and two children died of starvation in 1960, and how a fellow village committed suicide because she was afraid of being criticized for stealing rice of the people's commune canteen.
      覃士菊（1933年生）湖南省石门县白云乡鸡鸣桥村村民。在这段口述中，覃老人回忆了1960年间她老伴和俩孩子饿死的情况，以及村里一人偷食堂的大米被发现，因害怕被批斗自杀的故事。
    - Peng Jinxiu | 彭金秀, 2011
      Peng Jinxiu (b. 1931) was born in Ji Mingqiao Village, Baiyun Town, Changde City, Hunan Province. In this oral history, Peng recalls the Great Famine, when her second uncle wandered outside the village for food and her grandfather died of hunger.
      彭金秀1931年出生于湖南省常德市石门县白云镇鸡鸣桥村。在这段口述中，彭老人回忆了大饥荒时她的二舅为寻找食物去村外流浪和外公被饿死的经历。
    - Ou Renji | 欧仁基, 2010
      Ou Renji (b. 1937) is a resident of Jimingqiao Village, Baiyun Town, Shimen County, Hunan Province. In this interview, Ou recalls how he went to dig fern roots in mountains because his family were starving after the people's commune canteen was established, and how many people were criticized during that period.
      欧仁基（1937年生）是湖南省石门县白云乡鸡鸣桥村村民。在这段口述中，欧老人回忆了兴办食堂时期全家吃不饱，欧老人上山挖厥根的故事，以及当时整人批斗风盛行的情况。
    - Qin Guizhen | 覃贵珍/桂珍, 2010
      Qin Guizhen (b. 1930) is a resident of Jimingqiao Village, Baiyun Town, Shimen County, Hunan Province. In this interview, Qin recalls how she and her husband were criticized because of the landlord class status during the Cultural Revolution, and how her husband was jailed in a middle school and finally committed suicide. The filmmaker's description of this interview has been translated into English.
      覃贵珍（1930年生）湖南省石门县白云乡鸡鸣桥村村民。在这段口述中，覃老人回忆了文革时期老人家因地主身份接受批斗，覃老人老伴被关押在一所中学，最后自杀身亡的故事。
    - Tang Dongying | 唐冬英, 2010
      Tang Dongying (b. 1938) is a resident of Jimingqiao Village, Baiyun Town, Shimen County, Hunan Province. In this interview, Tang recalls how her husband attempted suicide after being labeled as a counter-revolutionary, how her children were discriminated at school because of their father's status, and how she and the four children were starving at home because the only manpower in the family, the father, was in jail. The filmmaker's description of this interview has been translated into English.
      唐冬英（1938年生）是湖南省石门县白云乡鸡鸣桥村村民。在这段口述中，唐老人回忆了文革时期，唐老人丈夫被打成反革命差点上吊，唐老人子女被歧视欺负，家里经济困难差点被饿死的情况。
    - Tang Chaogao | 唐超告, 2010
      Tang Chaogao (b. 1944) is a resident of Jimingqiao Village, Baiyun Town, Shimen County, Hunan Province. In this interview, Tang briefly talks about how he ate tree bark and grass seeds because of starvation when running the people's commune canteen.
      唐超告（1944年生）是湖南省石门县白云乡鸡鸣桥村村民。在这段口述中，唐老人简要讲述了兴办食堂期间吃不饱，吃树皮、草籽等充饥的经历。
    - Yang Guanya | 杨官亚, 2010
      Yang Guanya (b. 1946) is a resident of Jimingqiao Village, Baiyun Town, Shimen County, Hunan Province. In this interview, Yang recalls how he and his fellow pupils were forced to drop out of elementary to work, and how his village built a big earthen kiln to construct blast furnace during the Great Leap Forward. Yang also recounted in detail how every household took their own rice and bowls to the people's commune canteen to cook together, and how people collected wild herbs to eat because of hunger in this period.
      杨官亚（1946年生）湖南省石门县白云乡鸡鸣桥村村民。在这段口述中，杨老人回忆了大跃进时期自己所在的小学发动学生不上课参加劳动，村里开土窑炼铁的情况。杨老人还回忆了吃食堂时期每家拿着米和碗到食堂统一蒸制的，以及在食堂吃不饱吃野菜充饥的情况。
    - Li Zishan | 李子山, 2010
      Li Zishan (b. 1933) is a resident of Jimingqiao Village, Baiyun Town, Shimen County, Hunan Province. In this interview, Li recalls how his father stuffed to death when betting on rice with other people. Li also talks about his own experience of working day and night and stealing wheat to eat when starving.
      李子山（1933年生）是湖南省石门县白云乡鸡鸣桥村村民。在这段口述中，李老人讲述了自己父亲以米饭为赌注和别人打赌撑死，以及自己日夜劳动、饿了的时候偷麦子吃的情况。
    - Li Yuanqin | 李元芹, 2010
      Li Yuanqin (b. 1934) is a resident of Jimingqiao Village, Baiyun Town, Shimen County, Hunan Province. In this interview, Li recalls how the villagers were forced to work at night, how mud, lime, and soybean powder were used to make fake fertilizer to pass the superior authority's review, and how the bones of some villagers' ancestors were digged out of tombs to obtain farming fertilizer. Li worked for the people's commune canteen, where she witnessed Su Jinzhen, a blind woman villager, snatching food from other people, and some men villagers betting food coupons. The filmmaker's description of this interview has been translated into English.
      李元芹（1934年生）是湖南省石门县白云乡鸡鸣桥村村民。在这段口述中，李老人讲述了大跃进期间夜里出工，用泥巴、石灰、黄豆粉伪造肥料应付检查，以及挖村民祖坟做肥料的情况。李老人还讲述了兴办食堂期间，自己在食堂工作见到的瞎眼的苏金珍抢饭吃、男人用饭票作赌注打赌的情况。
  - Zhubaqiao Village | 常德市石门县白云乡竹坝桥村, 2010
    Zhubaqiao Village is located in Shimen County, Changde City, Hunan Province. Interviews in this sub-series were conducted and filmed by Jia Zhitan.
    竹坝桥村位于湖南省常德市石门县白云乡。村民的录像采访人是贾之坦。
    - Huang Meide | 黄梅德, 2010
      Huang Meide (b. 1919) is a resident of Zhuba Village, Baiyun Town, Shimen County, Hunan Province. In this interview, Huang recalls how she was starving at the people's commune canteen, and how her son and several older villagers died of starvation. Huang also recalls the villagers were forced to work at night, and the bones of some villagers' ancestors were digged out of tombs in order to obtain farming fertilizer during the Great Leap Forward. The filmmaker's descriptions of this interview have been translated into English.
      黄梅德（1919年生）是湖南省石门县白云乡竹坝桥村村民。在这段口述中，黄老人讲述了1958年兴办公社食堂时吃不饱挨饿，自己儿子及村里几位老人饿死的情况。黄老人还回忆了大跃进期间夜里也要出工劳动，以及为了积累肥料挖村民祖坟的情况。
  - Baiyangshan Village | 常德市石门县白云乡白羊山村, 2010
    Baiyangshan Village is located in Shimen County, Changde City, Hunan Province. Interviews in this sub-series were conducted and filmed by Jia Zhitan.
    白羊山村位于湖南省常德市石门县白云乡。村民的录像采访人是贾之坦。
    - Xiong Xuezhen|熊雪珍, 2010
      Xiong Xuezhen (b. 1923) is a resident of Baiyangshan Village, Baiyun Town, Shimen County, Hunan Province. In this interview, Xiong recalls how the women villagers were forced to make charcoal in the mountains and how the bones of tomb owners without progenies were digged out to make farming fertilizers after the people's commune canteen was established. Xiong also recounts how her family survived the famine because she and her husband were working for the canteen.
      熊雪珍（1923年生）湖南省石门县白云乡白羊山村村民。在这段口述中，熊老人回忆了1958年兴办食堂期间村里妇女带着小孩去山上烧炭、没有后人的墓主被挖出来做肥料、以及自己和老伴的工作与伙食有关全家免于饿死的情况。
  - Baiyun Xiang | 常德市石门县白云乡, 2010 and undated
    Baiyun Xiang is located in Shimen County, Changde City, Hunan Province. Interviews in this sub-series were conducted and filmed by Jia Zhitan.
    白云乡位于湖南省常德市石门县。村民的录像采访人是贾之坦。
    - Cai Daimiao | 才代淼
    - Jia Zhixiu | 贾之修
      Jia Zhixiu is a resident of Zhuxiangkou Village, Baiyun Town, Shimen County, Hunan Province. Jia was briefly mentioned in the interviews of Xiao Kaihan and Jia Zhenwen. Jie Zhixiu and Xiao Kaihan were village officials in charge of public security during the construction of Heping Reservoir, their job was to catch the enemy of the people.
      贾之修是湖南省石门县白云乡竹巷口村村民。贾的情况出现在肖开汉和贾珍文的口述中。贾之修和肖开汉是修和平水库时负责治安的村干部，负责抓阶级敌人。
    - Jin Shumei | 金淑梅
    - Liu Qinghe | 刘清河, 2010
    - Jia Guoqing | 贾国清
    - Jia Zhilan | 贾之兰, 2010
    - Cai Xianzheng | 才先整
    - Lin Xuelian | 林雪莲, 2010
    - Li Zifu | 李子富
      Li Zifu is a resident of Jimingqiao Village, Baiyun Town, Shimen County, Hunan Province. Li Zifu is Wu Yumei's husband. Li recalled his experience at the coal mine in 1958.
      李子富是湖南省石门县白云乡鸡鸣桥村村民。李子富是吴玉梅的丈夫。在这段口述中，李老人讲述了自己五八年在煤矿的经历。
    - Peng Gonge | 彭功娥, 2010
      Peng Gong'e (b. 1938) is a resident of Zhuxiangkou Village, Baiyun Town, Shimen County, Hunan Province. She's Wang Jisheng's wife. In this interview, Peng recalls how Hu Huanzhong was caught stealing rice from commue canteen and was beaten by village official. Her parents and many brothers and sisters suffered from starvation. Because her husband was a vilage official their life was bearable during the Commue Canteen period and she was probably the only woman who got pregnant in those days.